还有一单生意
There is one job.
黑道
Underworld?
迪幻字幕组   www.deefun.com
星球大战中文网   www.starwarschina.com
面谈
Face to face.
赏金猎人是个复杂的行当
Bounty hunting is a complicated profession.
■
时间轴： Lynki  moonywen
死亡证明我们也能接受
Proof of termination
■
翻译： aweng  staroyy  Yogaway  Freelee  侧卫突击队
不过报酬相对要低一些
is also acceptable for a lower fee.
前情回顾
曼达洛人
我的飞船被毁了  我被困在这了
My ship has been destroyed. I'm trapped here.
■
校订： 南方战士  moonywen
后期： moonywen  Lynki
那些是我的零件  是他们从我这偷走的
These are my parts. They stole them from me.
你可以交易
You can trade.
那我们要蛋  把蛋给我们带过来
蛋  什么蛋
The egg? What egg?
星球大战
曼鞑  我收到了你的信息  绝好的消息
Mando. I've received your transmission. Wonderful news.
回来的时候  把猎物直接给客户
Upon your return, deliver the quarry directly to the client.
我不清楚他想要把这东西吃掉  还是挂在墙上
I have no idea if he wants to eat it or hang it on his wall,
但是他非常焦虑
but he's very antsy.
一路平安  你知道在哪找我
Safe passage! You know where to find me.
这可不是玩具
It's not a toy.
小心点
Easy with that.
你别这么紧张
You take it easy.
太好了
Yes!
太好了  太好了  太好了
Yes, yes, yes!
太好了
Yes.
非常健康  太好了
Very healthy. Yes.
你真是名符其实
Your reputation was not unwarranted.
你把这活儿派给了多少人
How many fobs did you give out?
这物品对我来说极为重要
This asset was of extreme importance to me.
我要确保万无一失
I had to ensure its delivery.
不过胜者
But to the winner...
获得战利品
Go the spoils.
这么小的东西就值这么多赏金
Such a large bounty for such a small package.
你计划怎么处理它
What are your plans for it?
你在同类里还真是异乎寻常啊
How uncharacteristic of one of your reputation.
你既收了佣金  又收了报酬
You have taken both commission and payment.
忘记这些事情不正是行会准则吗
Is it not the Code of the Guild that these events are now forgotten?
这些贝斯卡足以使你的盔甲焕然一新了
That Beskar is enough to make a handsome replacement for your armor.
真可惜  在这艰苦岁月里找一个曼达洛人
Unfortunately, finding a Mandalorian in these trying times
可比找这些钢铁难多了
is more difficult than finding the steel.
曼达洛人
第三章
原 罪
这数量可以用来打造很多不同的东西
This amount can be shaped many ways.
我的护甲没法用了  可能得弄套新的
My armor has lost its integrity. I may need to begin again.
确实  我可以打造全套胸甲
Indeed. I can form a full cuirass.
它将与你现在的地位相称
This would be in order for your station.
无比荣幸
That would be a great honor.
必须警告你一下  这很引人注目
I must warn you. It will draw many eyes.
（注：这个曼达洛人叫帕兹·维兹拉（Paz Vizla））
这些是帝国冶金厂里铸造的
These were cast in an Imperial smelter.
是大清洗的赃物
These are the spoils of the Great Purge.
也是我们像沙鼠一样东躲西藏的原因
The reason that we live hidden like sand rats.
我们的秘密是幸存  我们的幸存是优势
Our secrecy is our survival. Our survival is our strength.
我们的优势曾是数量
Our strength was once in our numbers.
现在我们活在阴影里  一次一个从地里钻出来
Now we live in the shadows and only come above ground one at a time.
我们的世界被帝国撕得粉碎  这个软蛋还和他们拼桌
Our world was shattered by the Empire, with whom this coward shares tables.
帝国已不复存在
The Empire is no longer.
贝斯卡也回归了
And the Beskar has returned.
当你们选择曼达洛之道时
When one chooses to walk the Way of the Mandalore,
你们既是猎手又是猎物
you are both hunter and prey.
选择这条生活之道的人怎么会是软蛋？
How can one be a coward if one chooses this way of life?
你摘下过自己的头盔吗？
Have you ever removed your helmet?
没有
No.
它被其他人摘下来过吗？
Has it ever been removed by others?
从未
Never.
正是此道
This is the Way.
这是被什么弄坏的
What caused this damage?
泥角兽
A Mudhorn.
那你挣得了泥角兽作为私章
Then you have earned the Mudhorn as your signet.
我会把它刻上去
I shall craft it.
我不能接受  那次击杀不光彩
I can't accept. It wasn't a noble kill.
有个敌人帮了我
I was helped by an enemy.
为什么敌人要在战斗中帮你
Why would an enemy help you in battle?
它不知我与它为敌
It did not know it was my enemy.
既然你拒绝私章
Since you forgo a signet,
我将用余料为你打造一副口哨鸟
I shall use the excess to forge whistling birds.
口哨鸟很不错
Whistling birds will do well.
留一些给弃儿
Reserve some for the foundlings.
一向如此  弃儿即是未来
As it should always be. The foundlings are the future.
正是此道
This is the Way.
口哨鸟是用来应对多名敌人的强大防御武器
Whistling birds are a powerful defense against multiple enemies.
它们十分珍贵  请务必珍惜
Use them sparingly, for they are rare.
（注：天上飞过的是HMP机器人炮艇）
（注：这是一个B2战斗机器人）
听着  我告诉过你  我对你的借口毫无兴趣
Look, I told you. I'm not interested in your excuses!
你有过机会  废物  但你未能把握
You had your shot, dust breather, but you failed.
我不会给你定标器  滚出去
No pucks for you. Now get outta here.
曼鞑
Mando!
他们都恨你入骨  曼鞑
They all hate you, Mando.
因为你是个传奇
Because you're a legend!
他们有多少人得到了跟踪器
How many of them had tracking fobs?
所有人  所有人  但没人能像你一般完成交易
All of them. All of them! But not one of them closed the deal.
只有你  曼鞑  只有你
Only you, Mando. Only you.
随之而来的
And with it,
便是这个秒差距有史以来最丰厚的赏金
the richest reward this parsec has ever seen.
请坐  我的朋友
Please sit, my friend.
他们都在估量你身上贝斯卡钢的重量  但我不然
They're all weighing the Beskar in their minds, but not me.
不  就我来说  我会庆贺你的成功
No. I, for one, I celebrate your success.
因为这同样也是我的成功
Because it is my success as well.
该死  就连我也狠赚一笔
Hell! Even I am rich.
现在  我该如何向最宝贵的搭档聊表谢意呢
Now, how can I show my gratitude to my most valuable partner?
我想要下一份工作
I want my next job.
下一份工作
Next job?
你该放个假  尽情享乐
Take some time off. Enjoy yourself.
我请你去泡提列克养生浴吧
I'll take you to the Twi'lek healing baths.
我想要下一份工作
I want my next job.
行  好吧
Sure. Fine.
你们赏金猎人就是闲不下来  不是吗
You hunters like to keep busy, right?
这些活儿都要跑很远
Well, these are all far away.
越远  越好
The further, the better.
自己挑吧  你应得的
Well, take your pick. You've earned it.
挑了个最棒的活儿  从保释中逃跑的贵族儿子
That's the best one of the lot. A nobleman's son skipped bail.
（注：被通缉的是一个蒙卡拉马里人）
看来你要去一趟卡纳克海洋沙丘
Looks like you're headed to the ocean dunes of Karnac.
你知道他们会怎样对它吗
Any idea what they're gonna do with it?
对什么
With what?
那孩子
The kid.
我没问  这违反行会准则
I didn't ask. It's against the Guild Code.
他们替帝国办事  他们在这里干什么
They work for the Empire. What are they doing here?
帝国不存在了  曼鞑
The Empire is gone, Mando.
只剩下一群雇佣兵和军阀
All that are left are mercenaries and warlords.
但要是你觉得不妥
But if it bothers you,
尽管回核心世界  向新共和国举报
just go back to the Core and report them to the New Republic.
笑话
That's a joke.
曼鞑  好好花你的赏金
Mando, enjoy your rewards.
买一罐桶香料
Buy a camtono of spice.
到你从超空间出来时  就再也不会想这个了
By the time you come out of hyperdrive, you will have forgotten all about it.
我不管
I don't care.
我命令你取出所需材料  把这事情办妥
I order you to extract the necessary material and be done with it.
他明确指示我们  要把它活着带回
He has explicitly ordered us to bring it back alive.
赶紧完成任务  现在我已经不能保证你安全
Finish your business quickly, as I no longer can guarantee your safety.
检查外围
Check the perimeter.
（注：这是一个帝国审讯机器人）
不  不  不  不  求你
No, no, no, no, please.
求你  不要  不要  不
Please. No. No, no.
不要  求你
No, please.
求你别伤害他   那只是个孩子
Please don't hurt him. It's just a child.
求你  不要  不  求你  不要  不要  不
Please. No. No! Please. No. No, no.
你对它干什么了  你对它干什么了
What did you do to it? What did you do it?
我保护着他  我保护着他
I protected him. I protected him.
要不是我  他已经死了
If it wasn't for me, he would already be dead!
求你  求你  求你
Please! Please. Please.
看  那边
Look, there!
分开找  把他赶出来
Split up. We'll flush him out.
收到
Copy.
投降吧  你已经无
Give it up. There's nowhere to...
快
Hurry!
站住
Freeze!
不许动
Don't move.
举起手来
Hands up.
把枪放下
Drop the blaster.
等等  我手里的东西可价值连城
Wait. What I'm holding is very valuable.
放下了
Here.
转过来面朝着我
Now turn and face me.
站起来
Stand up!
欢迎回来  曼鞑
Welcome back, Mando!
把东西放下
Now put the package down.
都闪开  我要回我的飞船
Step aside. I'm going to my ship.
你把悬赏物放下  或许我会放你过去
You put the bounty down and perhaps I'll let you pass.
这孩子必须和我在一起
The kid's coming with me.
如果你是真的关心这孩子  那就把它放在陆行艇里
If you truly care about the kid, then you'll put it on the speeder
然后我们再来谈条件
and we'll discuss terms.
我怎么知道能相信你
How do I know I can trust you?
因为我是你唯一的希望
Because I'm your only hope.
快开
Drive.
Drive!
真是把好兵器
That's one impressive weapon!
接下来我要这么干
Here's what I'm gonna do.
我会带着这孩子走回飞船上  你们就干看着
I'm gonna walk to my ship with the kid and you're gonna let it happen.
不行  这样怎么样
No. How about this?
我们带走孩子
We take the kid,
如果你试图阻挠  我们就杀了你再把你分尸
and if you try to stop us, we kill you and we strip your body for parts.
别打中目标
Don't hit the target!
快走  我们来挡住他们
Get out of here! We'll hold them off!
你们必须要转移隐蔽所了
You're going to have to relocate the covert.
正是此道
This is the Way.
不要动  曼鞑
Hold it, Mando.
我本不想走到这一步
I didn't want it to come to this.
但你破坏了准则
But then you broke the Code.
我得弄一套这东西
I gotta get one of those.